

DANIEL VELASCO

Telecommunications Engineer

My profile

Telecommunications Engineer with experience in networks, programming, and development of cloud infrastructures. I have worked in technology companies in both the private and public sectors. One of my main achievements was extracting information from a United States Accounting software (QuickBooks) to develop XML for electronic billing. I am a person who is oriented around fulfilling and completing objectives, and I enjoy working with a team.

CONTACT



0989890946



linkedin.com/in/danielesteban-velasco



desteban.velpi@gmail.com



CUMBAYA, QUITO-ECUADOR

WORK EXPERIENCE

Blue Ocean Technologies

Post Sales Engineer | Quito, Ecuador

June 2022 - September 2022

- Monitoring the Citrix platform daily to make sure it is functioning properly.
- Testing Thin Clients to validate their functionality and compatibility with Citrix.
- Participating in meetings with various clients to check the functionality of the applications published by Citrix.
- Maintaining and developing good relationships with companies in Ecuador to acquire new customers.

Ministerio de Telecomunicaciones

Internship | Quito, Ecuador

Febuary 2022 - May 2022

- Gathering information and preparing a technical report on the updated broadband parameters in Ecuador.
- Verifying advanced mobile services on the maps of service providers.

SKILLS

- HTML
- Java Script
- CSS
- C#
- Python
- Matlab

SOFT SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Punctual
- Adaptable
- Problem Solving
- Organized

LANGUAGES

- Spanish: Native
- English: Intermediate Proficiency

AWARDS/ACTIVITIES

- Academic Scholarship for maintaining an above-average GPA
- Vice President of the IEEE-UDLA Student branch (January 2022-Present) Obtaining agreements with international companies such as Huawei-Mexico
- Used JavaScript, PHP, HTML, and CSS to help design Customer Relationship Management (CRM) for Safe Implant's website.

EDUCATION

Universidad de las Américas

Bachelors of Science in Telecommunications Engineering September 2018 - Present

Grade Point Average: 8.36/10

Unidad Educativa Mahanaym

High School Diploma January 2013 - December 2016

Final Grade Point Average: 9.23/10

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- 2023 | The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp
- 2022 | Responsive Web Design (Free Code Camp)
- 2022 Python Basics (Coursera)
- 2022 CCNA Security(Cisco)
- 2021 Enterprise Networking, Security, and Automation(Cisco)
- 2021 Switching, Routing, and Wireless Essentials(Cisco)
- 2021 Introduction to Networks(Cisco)
- 2022 Introduction to Programming with MATLAB (Coursera)